## SIYUAN DONG

Beijing, China • (+1)510-388-1436 • dongsiyuan@pku.edu.cn • https://www.linkedin.com/in/siyuan-dong/

# SUMMARY

I am a junior majoring in Computer Science from Peking University. I have accumulated a great amount of experience in research. My interest is in Data Stream Processing, Network, Systems and Machine Learning. I enjoy the process to discover, define and solve a problem. I am also good at implementing the ideas with codes, especially in C++ and python.

#### **EDUCATION**

Peking UniversityBeijing, ChinaBachelor of Science, ComputerExpected May 2024

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## **University of California – Berkeley**

Berkeley, CA

Research with Prof. Sylvia Ratnasamy

2023 - Present

Interesting Problems in Network System in IoT Scenario.

- Using data from different databases to do regression without leaking raw data nor violating user privacy.
- Real-time allocation of server into clouds to minimize the egress fee.

Peking UniversityBeijing, ChinaResearch with Prof. Tong Yang2022 - Present

Data Processing in Network and Database

- Key-Value Set Secure Aggregation and Privacy
  - Temporal membership query
  - Measurement of Per-flow latency distribution
  - Real-time frequency estimation of data streams
  - Real-time detection of interruption in data streams
  - Real-time detection of anomalies in data streams

### **SKILLS & TECHNIQUES**

- C/C++ programming
- Python programming
- Java programming
- SQL programming
- Front-end frameworks (Javascript, HTML) programming

## LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Peking University

• Beijing, China

• Director, Culture and Sports Department of EECS college 2022 - 2023

Director, Culture and Sports Department of EECS college
Built up the department from scratch. Held various cultural and sports activities to enrich students' campus lives.

Vice Chairman, Student Union of EECS college
Assisted chairman in running the Student Union of over 100 students. Directed various events.

Director, Comprehensive Administration Center in Culture and Sports Department of Peking University 2021 - 2022 Department operation. Contributed to various evening parties.

Section Chief, External Liaison Division in Student Union of EECS college
Closed deals with companies on sponsoring our events. Directed various events.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Yuhan Wu **Siyuan Dong,** Yi Zhou and Tong Yang. (2023). "KVSAgg: Secure Aggregation of Distributed Key-Value Sets". In: IEEE ICDE 2023 (to appear).

Zhuochen Fan Yubo Zhang, **Siyuan Dong** and Tong Yang. (2022). "HoppingSketch: More Accurate Temporal Mem bership Query and Frequency Query". In: IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (TKDE) 2022, pp. 1–6. doi: 10.1109/TKDE.2022.3221111.

## **WORKS IN PROGRESS**

**Siyuan Dong,** Wenhan Ma, Yuxuan Tian and Tong Yang. "InterruptionSketch: Real-time Detection of Interruption in Data Streams".

Zhuochen Fan, **Siyuan Dong**, Yuhan Wu and Tong Yang. "FriendlySketch: Accurately Estimating Per-Flow Latency Distribution".

## **REFERENCES**

**Tong Yang** 

Associate Professor of Computer Science School of Computer Science Peking University Beijing, China yangtongemail@gmail.com